<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kamil Wais on Kamil Wais</title>
    <link>https://kalimu.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kamil Wais on Kamil Wais</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Kamil Wais · Site created in R &amp; Blogdown · v2.4.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Wrażenia z pobytu na Uniwersytecie Notre Dame (USA)</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/wrazenia-z-pobytu-na-uniwersytecie-notre-dame-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/wrazenia-z-pobytu-na-uniwersytecie-notre-dame-usa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;center-for-research-computing-crc&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Center for Research Computing (CRC)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Od 1 sierpnia do 31 października 2017 r. miałem możliwość i ogromną satysfakcję gościć na Uniwersytecie Notre Dame w stanie Indiana. Pojechałem tam zaproszony przez dyrektora Center for Research Computing (CRC) prof. Jarka Nabrzyskiego, którego poznałem w Tokio rok wcześniej na konferencji plenarnej &lt;em&gt;Research Data Alliance&lt;/em&gt;. W USA spędziłem trzy miesiące jako wizytujący &lt;em&gt;assistant professor&lt;/em&gt;, przyglądając się pracy CRC, które jest jednym z kilku wydzielonych Centrów, działających na Uniwersytecie Notre Dame. W szczególności blisko współpracowałem z Center for Social Research (CRS). CRS jest jednostką blisko zintegrowaną z CRC i kierowaną przez Kate E. Mueller. CRS składa się z grupy osób specjalizujących się w analizie danych (Data Science) w badaniach społecznych. W sumie w całym CRC pracuje około 50 osób. Oprócz CRS w CRC działają też inne grupy: &lt;em&gt;High Performance Computing Group&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Software Development Group&lt;/em&gt; i &lt;em&gt;CyberInfrastructure Development Group&lt;/em&gt;. Taka struktura pozwala CRC na sprawną realizację misji, którą jest, między innymi, ułatwienie współpracy interdyscyplinarnej pomiędzy badaczami nauk społecznych i informatycznych. CRC zapewnia dostęp do rozbudowanej infrastruktury informatycznej i może np. zapewnić dostęp do mocy obliczeniowej ponad 30 000 rdzeni procesorowych, pozwalając m.in. na rozwój tzw. obliczeniowych nauk społecznych (Computational Social Science). CRC jest uznawane za jedno z najlepszych akademickich centrów obliczeniowych w Stanach. Notre Dame dysponuje obecnie w sumie dwudziestoma światowej klasy ośrodkami/centrami badawczymi (tzw. &lt;em&gt;core facilities&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;center-for-social-research-crs&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Center for Social Research (CRS)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRS z kolei zapewnia wsparcie pracownikom naukowym Uniwersytetu w zakresie gromadzenia, przechowywania, analizy, interpretacji i wizualizacji danych badawczych. W skład Centrum wchodzą osoby specjalizujące się w różnych obszarach i narzędziach. Cześć z tych osób pracuje nad doktoratami (pierwszymi lub kolejnymi). Nie mają oni obowiązków dydaktycznych. Oferowane są natomiast warsztaty dla chętnych studentów i pracowników naukowych. Podstawowym narzędziem analitycznym jest język programowania statystycznego R; wykorzystywany jest również Python. Mam bardzo pozytywne wrażenia z pracy w tym międzynarodowym środowisku osób (w składzie zespołu znajdowały się osoby pochodzące z Chin, Irlandii, czy Nepalu), zajmujących się Data Science w naukach społecznych. Niezwykle wartościowe było również różnorodne, interdyscyplinarne przygotowanie tych osób, często wychodzące daleko poza tylko nauki społeczne, np. podwójne studia z filozofii i informatyki, doktoraty z prawa oraz fizyki i statystyki, bioinformatyka, systemy GIS, czy formalna matematyka. CRS rozwija się coraz intensywniej, zatrudnia nowych konsultantów, rozbudowuje ofertę usługową. Plany rozwoju są ambitne, a potencjał duży również dzięki bliskiej integracji z CRC. Podczas swoich kontaktów z CRC/CRS byłem pod ogromnym wrażeniem dużej życzliwości i otwartości kadry zarządzającej, nie tylko w stosunku do mnie, ale i do wszystkich pracowników. To wszystko budowało od początku bardzo dobrą atmosferę do zespołowej pracy, współodpowiedzialność za projekty, lojalność i zaangażowanie ze strony pracowników. Dodać też trzeba, że ogromne wsparcie było również widoczne ze strony wszystkich wydziałów administracyjnych, jakie miałem okazję poznać (w moim przypadku szczególnie w sprawach formalno-wizowych).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;charakterystyka-uniwersytetu-notre-dame&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Charakterystyka Uniwersytetu Notre Dame&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uniwersytet Notre Dame został ufundowany w 1842 r. jako uniwersytet katolicki i od 175 lat nieprzerwanie zachowuje ten religijny charakter. Nie przeszkadza to jednak w tym, że zarówno pracownicy, jak i studenci reprezentują różne kraje, kultury i religie. Władze Uczelni jednoznacznie i otwarcie sprzeciwiają się wszelkim tendencjom rasistowskim czy antysemickim. Wolność słowa czy wyznania to wartości powszechnie akceptowane i pilnowane przez wszystkie strony. Podkreślana jest przez władze uczelni konieczność dialogu niezależnie od dzielących różnic, także światopoglądowych czy politycznych.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;kadra-i-studenci&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Kadra i studenci&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Na uniwersytecie pracuje około 1200 pełnoetatowych pracowników akademickich (nie licząc administracyjnych) i studiuje prawie 12 400 studentów, co daje stosunek ok. 10 studentów na jednego pracownika naukowego. Z tego też powodu grupy dydaktyczne liczące 12 osób uważane są za duże. Na około 20 000 podań w 2016 roku przyjęto na studia 3 655 osób, czyli 18.7% aplikujących. Składana jest duża liczba aplikacji z całego świata, mimo że czesne należy do jednego z wyższych w USA (średniorocznie ok. 50 tys. dolarów). Jednocześnie prawie 3/4 studentów pierwszych lat otrzymuje jakąś formę pomocy finansowej — w 2015/16 było to w sumie ponad 233 miliony dolarów. Na 2200 studentów poziomu graduate, 73% zdobywa doktoraty w 32 dyscyplinach. Około 97% otrzymuje pełne stypendia (&lt;em&gt;full-tuition scholarships&lt;/em&gt;). Ponad połowa studentów pierwszych lat studiuje również za granicą: w Australii, Brazylii, Chile, Chinach, Francji, Niemczech, Grecji, Irlandii, Izraelu, we Włoszech, Japonii, Jordanii, Meksyku, Rosji, Senegalu, Singapurze, Południowej Korei, Hiszpanii, Szwajcarii, Ugandzie i Wielkiej Brytanii. Na Notre Dame studiuje 1300 studentów międzynarodowych z 100 krajów. Dodatkowo, uczelnia gości każdego roku około 350 naukowców z różnych krajów. Na uczelni działa ponad 500 klubów studenckich i organizacji. 95% studentów kończy uczelnie z dyplomem, co daje Notre Dame miejsce w pierwszej piątce rankingu dla uczelni badawczych. Na świecie aktywnie działa największa w szkolnictwie wyższym sieć 270 klubów absolwentów Notre Dame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;rankingi&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rankingi&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krajowe rankingi dają Notre Dame miejsce (w zależności od konstrukcji) w pierwszej 25-tce, 15-tce lub nawet 10-tce najlepszych uniwersytetów w Stanach Zjednoczonych. Uczelnia jest też w ścisłej czołówce rankingu uniwersytetów, w którym rodzicie wybierają uczelnie, na jakich chcieliby, żeby studiowały ich dzieci (24% obecnych studentów to dzieci absolwentów Notre Dame). Uniwersytet jest również na pierwszym miejscu w rankingu instytucji szkolnictwa wyższego o charakterze katolickim. Wśród absolwentów Notre Dame są nobliści, senatorowie, pracownicy NASA, astronauci, kardynałowie czy osoby ze świata polityki, jak np. była Sekretarz Stanu Condoleezza Rice. Absolwenci Notre Dame pełnią najwyższe funkcje zarządcze (CEO) w około 25 collegach i uniwersytetach. W skład Notre Dame wchodzą również znane college i szkoły uznawane w kraju za jedne z najlepszych (np. Notre Dame Law School czy Mendoza College of Business).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;finanse&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finanse&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notre Dame dysponuje rocznym budżetem około 1.6 miliarda dolarów i obecnie może pochwalić się najwyższą ze wszystkich amerykańskich uniwersytetów sumą darowizn, wynoszącą łącznie ponad 10 miliardów dolarów. W roku 2016/17 sami absolwenci uczelni przekazali swojej Alma Mater w darowiznach 233 miliony dolarów. W ostatnim roku pozyskano również 138 milionów dolarów z samych grantów badawczych. Za pozyskanie ok. 10% tej sumy, czyli 14 mln dolarów, było współodpowiedzialne CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;kampus&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Kampus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kampus Uniwersytetu jest uważany za najpiękniejszy w Stanach Zjednoczonych i stanowi jedną z głównych atrakcji turystycznych w stanie Indiana. W roku akademickim 2015/2016 odwiedziło go ponad 1.8 miliona gości.&lt;br /&gt;
Na ponad 1260 akrach zlokalizowanych jest 171 budynków uniwersyteckich, co razem daje wartość ponad 3 miliardów dolarów. Budowane są kolejne budynki, w tym nowe centra badawcze. Moje miejsce pracy mieściło się w siedzibie CRS, zlokalizowanej w nowo wybudowanym, nowoczesnym i pięknym architektonicznie &lt;em&gt;Jenkins Hall&lt;/em&gt;. W obrębie kampusu mieszczą się boiska, pola golfowe, trasy spacerowo-biegowe wokół dwóch jezior, przystań dla żaglówek, dwie pływalnie (w tym jedna o wymiarach olimpijskich). Na kampusie zlokalizowany jest też stadion sportowy mieszczący 80 000 widzów, na którym regularnie odbywają się rozgrywki amerykańskiego footballu. W historii 150 kolejnych rozgrywek, za każdym razem, wykupione były wszystkie miejsca. Stadion od tego roku został wyposażony w największy stadionowy telebim. Kontrakt ze znaną marką amerykańską Under Armor na produkcję odzieży sportowej z logiem Notre Dame został wyceniony na prawie 100 mln dolarów, a wartość footballowej drużyny sportowej jest wyceniana na ponad 100 mln dolarów. Przy stadionie zlokalizowane jest również nowe, wyposażone w najnowszą technologię, studium telewizyjne, które przygotowuje transmisje telewizyjne wychodzące z Uniwersytetu. Główny budynek biblioteki uniwersyteckiej (a jest ich kilka) ma 14 pięter i w momencie ukończenia budowy był największą biblioteką uniwersytecką na świecie. Uniwersytet ma również własną elektrownię, straż pożarną, dwie kliniki (dla studentów i kadry naukowej) i własną policję, która posiada jurysdykcję na terenie kampusu niezależną od lokalnej policji. Wydawnictwo uniwersyteckie ma 1000 książek w druku i ponad 50 nowych tytułów rocznie. Uniwersytet Notre Dame posiada również swoje filie w Londynie, Beijing, Dublinie, Jeruzalem i Rzymie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;eventy&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Eventy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pobyt w Notre Dame to również była doskonała okazja do udziału w otwartych wykładach, seminariach, spotkaniach, warsztatach i uroczystościach. Z ciekawszych wykładów warto wspomnieć wykład prof. Anny Grzymały-Busse ze Stanford University, która odbierała jednocześnie prestiżową nagrodę z swoją książkę &lt;em&gt;Nations under God&lt;/em&gt;, czy wykład &lt;em&gt;Citizenship in a Global Age&lt;/em&gt; prowadzony przez Horsta Koehlera — byłego prezydenta Niemiec, obecnie przedstawiciela Narodów Zjednoczonych na zachodnią Saharę. Wartościowe było osobiste poznanie Hadley’a Wickhama (Chief Scientist w RStudio), cieszącego się ogromnym uznaniem w społeczności osób zajmujących się Data Science, który przybył do Notre Dame z gościnnym wykładem w ramach cyklu zaproszonych wykładów dla studentów kierunku Data Science. Interesujące były również spotkania z udziałem osób ze świata polityki amerykańskiej, np. z byłą Sekretarz Stanu Condoleezzą Rice, szefami sztabów Baracka Obamy i Georga Busha, czy byłym dyrektorem CIA. Brałem również udział w bardzo wartościowych i inspirujących warsztatach &lt;em&gt;Writing Successful Grants&lt;/em&gt; prowadzonych przez Roberta Portera — byłego dyrektora Research Development na University of Tenessee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ogólnie swój pobyt oceniam jako bardzo udany, przekraczający znacznie moje wcześniejsze oczekiwania. O wynikach prac naukowych prowadzonych w Notre Dame będę informował w odpowiednim czasie w innym miejscu na swojej stronie WWW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://kalimu.github.io/img/photos/nd_01.jpg&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://kalimu.github.io/img/photos/nd_02.jpg&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://kalimu.github.io/img/photos/nd_03.jpg&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://kalimu.github.io/img/photos/nd_04.jpg&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://kalimu.github.io/img/photos/nd_05.jpg&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://kalimu.github.io/img/photos/nd_06.jpg&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://kalimu.github.io/img/photos/nd_07.jpg&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://kalimu.github.io/img/photos/nd_08.jpg&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://kalimu.github.io/img/photos/nd_09.jpg&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://kalimu.github.io/img/photos/nd_10.jpg&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://kalimu.github.io/img/photos/nd_11.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determinants of willingness to study in Poland among members of Polish Diaspora</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/publication/determinants-of-willingness-to-study-in-poland-among-members-of-polish-diaspora/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/publication/determinants-of-willingness-to-study-in-poland-among-members-of-polish-diaspora/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Data Science in Pursuit of Long-Term Relationship Between Respondents and Social Researchers</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/talk/2017-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/talk/2017-chicago/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Tidyverse. Hadley Wickham lecture at Notre Dame University</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/welcome-to-the-tidyverse-hadley-wickham-lecture-at-notre-dame-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/welcome-to-the-tidyverse-hadley-wickham-lecture-at-notre-dame-university/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my research visit at Notre Dame University I had the pleasure to participate in Hadley Wickham’s lecture &lt;em&gt;Welcome to the Tidyverse&lt;/em&gt; and meet Hadley in person. Hadley’s talks are always well-structured and worth listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hadley Wickham has been a prime mover in releasing R upon the masses, enabling hordes of unsuspecting would-be researchers to process and visualize data in ways they never dreamed of. The tidyverse, the culmination of years of effort in the R language, is a universe of packages that facilitate a grammar of data, graphics, and modeling that allows even beginners to speak the language of data science fluently. Author of several books on programming and dozens(!) of R packages that are among the most widely used in the realm of data, Hadley Wickham invites you personally to experience the thrill of diving deep into data, discovering unknown treasures, and coming out on the other side with a fuller understanding of the way in which the world works! Hadley Wickham is the Chief Scientist at RStudio and an Adjunct Professor of Statistics at the University of Auckland, Stanford University, and Rice University. He builds computational and cognitive tools that make data science easier, faster, and more fun. This event was hosted by the MS-ACMS Data Science program and was co-sponsored by the Mendoza College of Business MSBA program and the Office of the Provost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://kalimu.github.io/img/photos/hadley.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;May the RStudio be with you!&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;May the RStudio be with you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminarium z udziałem prof. Philipa Zimbardo </title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/seminarium-z-udzialem-prof-philip-zimbardo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/seminarium-z-udzialem-prof-philip-zimbardo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;W sobotę (24.06) odbyło się na WSIiZ insprujące seminarium z udziałem on-line prof. P.Zimbardo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philip Zimbardo był w 1971 roku liderem sławnego Stanfordzkiego Eksperymentu Więziennego i świadkiem-ekspertem w sprawie więzienia Abu Ghraib. Autor wpływowych książek: The Time Paradox: The New Psychology of Time That Will Change Your Life i The Lucifer Effect: Understanding How Good People Turn Evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warto zapoznać się z projektem Profesora Zimbardo:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://heroicimagination.org/&#34;&gt;Heroic Imagination Project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Przystępne krótkie wykłady można natomiast znaleźć na stronie:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/speakers/philip_zimbardo&#34;&gt;TED Talks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Więcej o samym seminarium &lt;a href=&#34;https://wsiz.rzeszow.pl/pl/Uczelnia/Wydarzenia/Strony/profesor-philip-zimbardo-z-wykladem-podczas-seminarium-doktoranckiego-wsiiz.aspx&#34;&gt;na stronie WSIiZ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closed Open Data</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/project/gus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/project/gus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;summary&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this research project we analyze barriers and bad practices in accessing Open Administrative Data in Poland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Data Science &amp; Programming Skills &amp; Tools</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/my-data-science-and-programming-skills-and-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/my-data-science-and-programming-skills-and-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a selection of my Data Science and Programming skills and tools that turned out to be helpful in my work and I believe are important for any Data Scientist as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last update of this post was done: 2018-04-23.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;data-science-skills&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Data Science Skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Manipulation&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficient data manipulation in R;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;dplyr&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;data.table&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;reshape2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with dates and time-series;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;lubridate&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;xts&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reproducible Analyses&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RStudio IDE, Markdown, LaTeX;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;RMarkdown&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;knitr&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Databases and Data Formats&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MySQL, MongoDB, JSON, XML, Excel, CSV, shapefiles, Linked Open Data / SPARQL, etc.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;mongolite&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;jsonlite&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Acquisition&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;parallel web-scrapping; working with REST API;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;httr&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;RCurl&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;rvest&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;RSelenium&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Text-mining&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;regular expressions; stemming with dictionary method;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;stringr&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;tm&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;genderizeR&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Qualitative Analyses&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;RQDA&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On-Line Surveys (CAWI)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;advanced on-line surveys in &lt;code&gt;LimeSurvey&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;LimeRick&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Networks Analyses&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;visualizing and analyzing networks in &lt;code&gt;Gelphi&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;programming dynamic networks simulations in &lt;code&gt;NetLogo&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Visualization&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;static and interactive data visualization;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ggvis&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;waffle&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dashboards and data reporting via WWW apps;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Shiny&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;shinydashboard&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;shinyjs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communicating Results&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reports and presentations in &lt;code&gt;Tableau&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;PowerPoint&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;HTML5&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Rmarkdown&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;isoslides&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statistical Analysis &amp;amp; Machine Learning&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multiple linear regression, logistic regression, ordinal logistic regression, Principal Component Analysis (PCA), factor analysis, segmentation analysis, cluster analysis (k-means, hierarchical clustering), supervised / unsupervised learning,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;neural networks, Support Vector Machines (SVM), decision trees, Random Forests, Ridge Regression, LASSO, elastic net regularization, K-fold cross-validation, bootstraping with &lt;code&gt;caret&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;survival analysis with &lt;code&gt;survival&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time series analysis (ARIMA, TBATS) with &lt;code&gt;forecast&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big Data Tools&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;familiarity with &lt;code&gt;Spark&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;sparklyr&lt;/code&gt; in R;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;familiarity with &lt;code&gt;MapReduce&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Hadoop&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Pig&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Data Science Tools&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;familiarity with &lt;code&gt;SPSS&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;SAS&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Octave&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;RapidMiner&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Excel VisualBasic&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;R Revolution Enterprise&lt;/code&gt; / &lt;code&gt;Microsoft R&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;programming-skills&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Programming Skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programming in R&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;code versioning with &lt;code&gt;RStudio IDE&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Git&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;GitHub&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;functional programming with &lt;code&gt;purrr&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reactive programming with &lt;code&gt;Shiny&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;shinyjs&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;parallel programming with &lt;code&gt;parallel&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R package development&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;package distribution with &lt;code&gt;GitHub&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;CRAN&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;preparing package documentation with &lt;code&gt;roxygen2&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unit testing with &lt;code&gt;testthat&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet technologies&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;HTML5&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;CSS3&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;JavaScript&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;familiarity with &lt;code&gt;MongoDB&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;MEAN&lt;/code&gt; Stack, &lt;code&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Linux&lt;/code&gt; servers;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other programming languages&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;familiarity with &lt;code&gt;Python&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;C++&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Java for Android&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; Android Studio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Środowisko fizyczne i społeczne oraz jakość funkcjonowania szkoły a zdrowie subiektywne i zachowania zdrowotne nastolatków. Raport końcowy z realizacji projektu badawczego</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/publication/srodowisko-fizyczne-i-spoleczne-oraz-jakosc-funkcjonowania-szkoly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/publication/srodowisko-fizyczne-i-spoleczne-oraz-jakosc-funkcjonowania-szkoly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Raport został przedstawiony przez prof. Bogusława Śliwerskiego na jego blogu:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://sliwerski-pedagog.blogspot.com/2017/06/jakosc-szkoy-zdrowie-uczniow.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://sliwerski-pedagog.blogspot.com/2017/06/jakosc-szkoy-zdrowie-uczniow.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources: Programming &amp; Data Science in R</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/resources-programming-data-science-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/resources-programming-data-science-in-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is an annotated bibliography of helpful resources for programming and doing Data Science in R. I will try to expand this list and add some short recommendations in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last update of this post was done: 2018-04-23.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;books-on-line-printed&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Books (on-line &amp;amp; printed)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hadley Wickham, &lt;em&gt;Advanced R&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The book is designed primarily for R users who want to improve their programming skills and understanding of the language. It should also be useful for programmers coming to R from other languages, as it explains some of R’s quirks and shows how some parts that seem horrible do have a positive side.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://adv-r.had.co.nz/&#34;&gt;[See more…]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-top&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-bottom&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hadley Wickham, &lt;em&gt;R packages&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;[…] You’ll learn how to turn your code into packages that others can easily download and use. Writing a package can seem overwhelming at first. So start with the basics and improve it over time. It doesn’t matter if your first version isn’t perfect as long as the next version is better.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://adv-r.had.co.nz/&#34;&gt;[See more…]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-top&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-bottom&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R Core Team, &lt;em&gt;Writing R Extensions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Official R Package documentation. Mandatory reading for R Package developers but not very user-friendly.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/doc/manuals/r-release/R-exts.html&#34;&gt;[See more…]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;[R package development]&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-top&#34; style=&#34;width: 65%&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-bottom&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marek Gągolewski, &lt;em&gt;Programowanie w języku R. Analiza danych. Obliczenia. Symulacje&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Formalne, ustrukturyzowane podejście do języka. Raczej dla osób powyżej początkujących.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://ksiegarnia.pwn.pl/produkt/213568/programowanie-w-jezyku-r.html&#34;&gt;[See more…]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-top&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-bottom&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrea Spanò, &lt;em&gt;Ramarro. R for Developers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;For more advanced R programmers. Included topics about OOP, debugging and profiling, parallel computation, and C++ integration via Rcpp.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quantide.com/ramarro-r-for-developers/&#34;&gt;[See more…]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-top&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-bottom&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dan Navarro, &lt;em&gt;Learning Statistics with R&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Over 560 pages of very good introductory materials into statistics and R. Strongly recommended for beginners in statistics.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://health.adelaide.edu.au/psychology/ccs/teaching/lsr/&#34;&gt;[See more…]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-top&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-bottom&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;video-courses&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Video Courses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jared P. Lander, &lt;em&gt;R Programming LiveLessons. Fundamentals to Advanced&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;16+ Hours of Video Instruction. R Programming: Fundamentals to Advanced is a tour through the most important parts of R, the statistical programming language, from the very basics to complex modeling. It covers reading data, programming basics, visualization. data munging, regression, classification, clustering, modern machine learning and more.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.informit.com/store/r-programming-livelessons-video-training-fundamentals-9780133743272&#34;&gt;[See more…]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-top&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-bottom&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;massive-open-online-courses-moocs&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Massive Open Online Courses (MOOCs)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DataCamp.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Interactive programming and Data Science courses in R and Python. Some of them are free of charge, some of them are premium courses. High quality materials, lots of interactive excercises, well-known data scientists as authors of the courses. Highly recommended.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datacamp.com/&#34;&gt;[See more…]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-top&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-bottom&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;formal-education&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Formal Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Master of Computer Science in Data Science (MCS-DS)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;With tuition under $20K, the MCS-DS is one of the most affordable gateways to one of the most lucrative and fastest growing careers of the new millennium. The MCS-DS builds expertise in four core areas of computer science: data visualization, machine learning, data mining and cloud computing, in addition to building valuable skill sets in statistics and information science with courses taught in collaboration with the University’s Statistics Department and iSchool (ranked #1 among Library and Information Studies Schools.)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/university-programs/masters-in-computer-data-science&#34;&gt;[See more…]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Studia podyplomowe: Metody statystyczne w biznesie. Warsztaty z oprogramowaniem SAS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Adresatami studiów podyplomowych „Metody statystyczne w biznesie” są wszystkie osoby pracujące na co dzień z danymi, zajmujący się ich analizą, przetwarzaniem, jak również będące odbiorcami takich analiz. Oferta skierowana jest do analityków, specjalistów ds. badań, jak również kadry menedżerskiej. Wszystkie zajęcia mają charakter warsztatów z wykorzystaniem oprogramowania SAS [niestety nie R, ale również warte polecenia] i odbywają się w pracowni komputerowej.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://coin.wne.uw.edu.pl/pwojcik/podyplomowe_statystyka/&#34;&gt;[See more…]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-top&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;star-ratings-css-bottom&#34;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;★&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Studia podyplomowe: Inżynieria danych – Big Data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Adresatami studiów są zatem osoby pragnące pogłębić i poszerzyć swoją wiedzę teoretyczną oraz praktyczne umiejętności jej wykorzystania w obszarze nowoczesnych informatycznych metod i narzędzi analityki Big Data, ze szczególnym uwzględnieniem zastosowań biznesowych.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://bigdatacenter.pl/?page_id=166&#34;&gt;[See more…]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building static homepage with R &amp; blogdown</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/building-static-homepage-with-r-and-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/building-static-homepage-with-r-and-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This new homepage is a static website generated in R (!) with the help of brilliant &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; package by Yihui Xie. &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; is the site engine and it also uses amazing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic&#34;&gt;Academic theme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More about the blogdown R package you can find here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some additional usefull posts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://daijiang.name/en/2017/03/30/updating-website-with-hugo-and-blogdown/&#34;&gt;Updating website with Hugo and Blogdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://proquestionasker.github.io/blog/Making_Site/&#34;&gt;Making Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/articles/quick-start-setting-up-a-custom-domain/&#34;&gt;Quick Start setting up a custom domain with GitHub pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Loan Companies in Poland: Does Empirical Evidence Justify Regulatory Transition?</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/publication/personal-loan-companies-in-poland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/publication/personal-loan-companies-in-poland/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External evaluation of the school and academic achievements in relation to alcohol drinking and delinquent behaviour among secondary school students / Wyniki zewnętrznej ewaluacji szkoły i osiągnięcia w nauce a picie alkoholu i wykroczenia gimnazjalistów</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/publication/external-evaluation-of-the-school-and-academic-achievements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/publication/external-evaluation-of-the-school-and-academic-achievements/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation of R package LimeRick on eRum</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/presentation-of-r-package-limerick-on-erum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/presentation-of-r-package-limerick-on-erum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: The online static version of the presentation is available here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://rpubs.com/kalimu/erum&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://rpubs.com/kalimu/erum&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you for all the feedback!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In two days, from 12 to 14 October, 2016 in Poznan (Poland) will take place the conference “eRum 2016: european R users meeting“. I will give a talk about new R package: LimeRick. LimeRick enables close connection between two important open-source projects: R and LimeSurvey. LimeSurvey is the most advanced open-source system for on-line survey and Computer Aided Web Interviewing (CAWI) and together with R they offer advanced ecosystem for gathering and analyzing declarative data. But the LimeRick package will be able to do a lot more. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first public presentation of the prototype of a new R package that provides useful connection between R and the most popular open-source web scripts for on-line surveys (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.LimeSurvey.org&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://www.LimeSurvey.org&lt;/a&gt;). The package aims to enable and simplify the work flow of reproducible CAWI research in Social Science; preparing templates for ad hoc and real-time analysis, performing detailed meta-analysis, archiving and monitoring responses directly from R. With the LimeRick package one can import pre-processed data from an on-line survey with an R script (with the use of RemoteConrol2 API or with non-API solution). Then, the data can be processed analytically by an R script and automatically reported with the use of shiny package. The whole process can be pre-programmed and performed without the researcher interference. This enables to build data products based on declarative data from on-line surveys, which are processed, analyzed, and visualized on-line and in real time. It can be of use for performing automatic tracking studies with real-time KPIs monitoring (e.g. for a customer satisfaction survey). The package will be also linked to a tool for unique, advanced analysis of meta-data from an on-line survey, which has already been alpha tested during large CAWI research project. As the early prototype of the package is presented, the presentation will end with a call for collaboration for developing and testing the package in different usage cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS. Thanks to Carsten Shmitz (the main developer of LimeSurvey) after my presentation participants interested in LimeSurvey and LimeRick projects will be able to get some gifts (cool promotional materials of LimeSurvey open-source project – see the picture below). See you then!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender Prediction Methods based on First Names with genderizeR</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/publication/gender-prediction-methods-based-on-first-names-with-genderizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/publication/gender-prediction-methods-based-on-first-names-with-genderizer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When using the genderizeR R package in your work, please cite also the article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@article{RJ-2016-002,
  author = {Kamil Wais},
  title = {{Gender Prediction Methods Based on First Names with
          genderizeR}},
  year = {2016},
  journal = {{The R Journal}},
  url = {https://journal.r-project.org/archive/2016/RJ-2016-002/index.html},
  pages = {17--37},
  volume = {8},
  number = {1}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My impression from Research Data Alliance (RDA) 7th Plenary Meeting in Tokyo</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/my-impression-from-research-data-alliance-rda-7th-plenary-meeting-in-tokyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/my-impression-from-research-data-alliance-rda-7th-plenary-meeting-in-tokyo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seventh RDA Plenary was organized in Tokyo in March 2016 in close partnership with the Japan Science and Technology Agency (JST). This was the first time a plenary took place in Asia. One of the reason was to expand the reach of the RDA far beyond America and Europe through increase in organization’s memberships from Asia region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one of the winners of the RDA Early Career European Researchers &amp;amp; Scientists Working with Data (RDA P7 Financial Support Programme), I had a unique opportunity and honor to see with my own eyes how activities in RDA look like. Now, I can share with you my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, RDA is a truly global (international and intercontinental) organization with mission to build the social and technical bridges that enable open sharing of research data. The global character can be seen on every level. For example, to establish a so called „Working Group” you need to cooperate with researchers from at least 3 different continents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those Working &amp;amp; Interest Groups are fully community-driven entities, based on volunteers’ work, consensus and a true passion for Open Research Data and Open Science in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The atmosphere inside Working &amp;amp; Interest Groups, as well during the Plenary, is very friendly without artificial distance based on level of experience or position in the academic hierarchy. One has an opportunity to have fascinating talks about science and data with leading word researchers and experts from different industries, disciplines and the most famous research centers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RDA plenaries themselves are not like traditional academic conferences. Apart from a global perspective on sharing research data, they lack meaningless paper presentations. Instead, they are focusing on collaborative effort to produce applicable outcomes and recommendations. These outcomes are results of consensus achieved mainly through on-line and off-line discussions. This approach turned out to be effective, as the RDA recommendations are quickly and widely adopted by recognized institutions and organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There also comes a great value from working in such inter-national and inter-cultural environment. It is fascinating to hear about different perspectives and solutions specific to cultural and local conditions. Moreover, there is a mixture of all possible disciplines, from agriculture to astronomy. Many of those disciplines have different perspectives, different approaches to working with research data, which makes a common dialog sometimes difficult but also rewarding when we can agree on some common solutions to different problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the 7th Plenary I have participated in several Working &amp;amp; Interest Group sessions. Two of them were organized by Data Fabric Interest Group. The term „Data Fabric” (German metaphor for a „factory”) describes the Data Cycle: creating new data collections, processing, registering, describing, storing, preserving and publishing the data. The goal of the group is to improve the cycle, make the cycle more efficient and cost-effective. Considering that the most time data scientists spend on data management, improving such processes will have a huge impact on science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although, I am not a librarian, I found the IG Libraries for Research Data session very interesting as well. It was called Applying Global Information Sharing and Collaboration in Libraries to Local Practice, and showed what impressive work librarians from all over the world can do. Solutions were presented from Japan, Korea and Singapore. Some countries are at the beginning of the process of implementing links between Open Access papers and repositories with Open Research Data. However, their „beginnings” are still very impressive (for example two levels of software platforms for open research data in Korea; one for university repositories and one for central platform that aggregates metadata from local repositories).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by this session I just can hope that someday many modern Polish librarians will be engaged in developing Open Access, Open Research Software and Open Data infrastructure and Open Science culture in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after the Plenary discussion the Array Database Assessment WG was created. It focuses on benchmarking, overview and best usage of Array Databases in science, engineering, and beyond. There are big hopes for efficiency and scalability of array databases. If they meet the expectations they may dominate the market of Big Data technologies in close future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were many interesting topics in the plenary sessions as well. Jean-Claude Burgelman from the European Commission, talked about European Open Science Cloud project. It might have an impressive effect on changing of many of European researchers’ workflows. I am looking forward to evaluate it myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the round table in Open Symposium: Data-driven Science – The trigger of Scientific development, I got an impression that data-driven approach in science is fairy more appreciated and recognized in Japan than in Poland, where still dominates hypothesis-driven approach especially in social sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also impressed with IT science infrastructure in Japan, and a research project that allows to identify dangerous places on streets where drivers hit breaks rapidly, thanks to spatial-temporal analysis based on data collected from GPS and accelerometers installed in cars. Considering that similar data are produced daily by approximately 100 000 users of some mobile application in Poland, it would be great if similar study would help to improve safety on Polish roads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also come back with positive feedback on my poster presented in Tokyo titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://kalimu.github.io/talk/2016-tokyo/&#34;&gt;International On-line Expert Access Panel for Open Science Development&lt;/a&gt;. With some institutional and organizational support such project seems to be feasible and I believe that it can bring a lot of valuable data from science community. Anyone interested in the project is welcome to &lt;a href=&#34;https://kalimu.github.io/#contact&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I am back to Poland, but I feel that this was only the beginning of me thinking constantly about science that always takes into account the open research data postulates. Now it is also the time to promote RDA activities in my country, with the vision of global science community that works together and shares its research data for the benefits of all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
