<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rpackage on Kamil Wais</title>
    <link>https://kalimu.github.io/tags/rpackage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rpackage on Kamil Wais</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2018 Kamil Wais · Site created in R &amp; Blogdown · v3.5.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kalimu.github.io/tags/rpackage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Native Declarative Data Collection with Question and Survey Instant Feedback in R&amp;Shiny</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/talk/2018-budapest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/talk/2018-budapest/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from eRum 2018: European R User Conference in Budapest</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/2018-05-23-notes-from-erum-2018-european-r-user-conference-in-budapest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/2018-05-23-notes-from-erum-2018-european-r-user-conference-in-budapest/</guid>
      <description>The second eRum was organized this year in Budapest (Hungary) and gathered ~500 participants (mostly, but not only, from Europe). It was a great event and a worthy successor of the first eRum organized in Poznań (Poland) two years ago.
In the Workskop Day I participated in two workshops:
 Efficient R programming by Colin Gillespie (author of the Efficient R Programming book by O’Reilly) Building a package that lasts by Colin Fay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Tidyverse. Hadley Wickham lecture at Notre Dame University</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/welcome-to-the-tidyverse-hadley-wickham-lecture-at-notre-dame-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/welcome-to-the-tidyverse-hadley-wickham-lecture-at-notre-dame-university/</guid>
      <description>During my research visit at Notre Dame University I had the pleasure to participate in Hadley Wickham’s lecture Welcome to the Tidyverse and meet Hadley in person. Hadley’s talks are always well-structured and worth listening.
Hadley Wickham has been a prime mover in releasing R upon the masses, enabling hordes of unsuspecting would-be researchers to process and visualize data in ways they never dreamed of. The tidyverse, the culmination of years of effort in the R language, is a universe of packages that facilitate a grammar of data, graphics, and modeling that allows even beginners to speak the language of data science fluently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genderizeR</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/project/genderizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/project/genderizer/</guid>
      <description>R package for gender prediction based on first namesThe package uses genderize.io API to predict gender from first names extracted from text vector. The accuracy of prediction could be control by two parameters: counts of a first name in the database and probability of prediction.
README, BugReports and development repository on GitHub: https://github.com/kalimu/genderizeR
The package webpage on CRAN:
http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/genderizeR
Article &amp;amp; Citations:When using the genderizeR R package in your work, please cite also the article:Kamil Wais, Gender Prediction Methods Based on First Names with genderizeR, The R Journal,Vol.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>