<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>conferences on Kamil Wais</title>
    <link>https://kalimu.github.io/categories/conferences/</link>
    <description>Recent content in conferences on Kamil Wais</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2018 Kamil Wais · Site created in R &amp; Blogdown · v3.7.2</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kalimu.github.io/categories/conferences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BigSurv18: Big Data Meets Survey Science Conference and Supercomputing Center in Barcelona</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/2018-11-05-bigsurv18-big-data-meets-survey-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/2018-11-05-bigsurv18-big-data-meets-survey-science/</guid>
      <description>Conference Recently, I was representing 7N on BigSurv18 Conference in Barcelona . The conference title was Big Data Meets Survey Science and this was the first conference with the aim of exploring new statistical frontiers at the intersection of Survey Science and Big Data. The conference was organized by The European Survey Research Association (ESRA) and was held at the Research and Expertise Center of Survey Methodology at the Universitat Pompeu Fabra in Barcelona.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from eRum 2018: European R User Conference in Budapest</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/2018-05-23-notes-from-erum-2018-european-r-user-conference-in-budapest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/2018-05-23-notes-from-erum-2018-european-r-user-conference-in-budapest/</guid>
      <description>The second eRum was organized this year in Budapest (Hungary) and gathered ~500 participants (mostly, but not only, from Europe). It was a great event and a worthy successor of the first eRum organized in Poznań (Poland) two years ago.
In the Workskop Day I participated in two workshops:
 Efficient R programming by Colin Gillespie (author of the Efficient R Programming book by O’Reilly) Building a package that lasts by Colin Fay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation of R package LimeRick on eRum</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/2016-10-09-limerick-erum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/2016-10-09-limerick-erum/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: The online static version of the presentation is available here: http://rpubs.com/kalimu/erum. Thank you for all the feedback!
In two days, from 12 to 14 October, 2016 in Poznan (Poland) will take place the conference “eRum 2016: european R users meeting“. I will give a talk about new R package: LimeRick. LimeRick enables close connection between two important open-source projects: R and LimeSurvey. LimeSurvey is the most advanced open-source system for on-line survey and Computer Aided Web Interviewing (CAWI) and together with R they offer advanced ecosystem for gathering and analyzing declarative data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My impression from Research Data Alliance (RDA) 7th Plenary Meeting in Tokyo</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/2016-03-31-rda-tokyo/research-data-alliance-rda-7th-plenary-meeting-in-tokyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/2016-03-31-rda-tokyo/research-data-alliance-rda-7th-plenary-meeting-in-tokyo/</guid>
      <description>Seventh RDA Plenary was organized in Tokyo in March 2016 in close partnership with the Japan Science and Technology Agency (JST). This was the first time a plenary took place in Asia. One of the reason was to expand the reach of the RDA far beyond America and Europe through increase in organization’s memberships from Asia region.
As one of the winners of the RDA Early Career European Researchers &amp;amp; Scientists Working with Data (RDA P7 Financial Support Programme), I had a unique opportunity and honor to see with my own eyes how activities in RDA look like.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>