<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Kamil Wais</title>
    <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Kamil Wais</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2018 Kamil Wais · Site created in R &amp; Blogdown · v3.1.2</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kalimu.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Wrażenia z pobytu na Uniwersytecie Notre Dame (USA)</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/wrazenia-z-pobytu-na-uniwersytecie-notre-dame-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/wrazenia-z-pobytu-na-uniwersytecie-notre-dame-usa/</guid>
      <description>Center for Research Computing (CRC)Od 1 sierpnia do 31 października 2017 r. miałem możliwość i ogromną satysfakcję gościć na Uniwersytecie Notre Dame w stanie Indiana. Pojechałem tam zaproszony przez dyrektora Center for Research Computing (CRC) prof. Jarka Nabrzyskiego, którego poznałem w Tokio rok wcześniej na konferencji plenarnej Research Data Alliance. W USA spędziłem trzy miesiące jako wizytujący assistant professor, przyglądając się pracy CRC, które jest jednym z kilku wydzielonych Centrów, działających na Uniwersytecie Notre Dame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Tidyverse. Hadley Wickham lecture at Notre Dame University</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/welcome-to-the-tidyverse-hadley-wickham-lecture-at-notre-dame-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/welcome-to-the-tidyverse-hadley-wickham-lecture-at-notre-dame-university/</guid>
      <description>During my research visit at Notre Dame University I had the pleasure to participate in Hadley Wickham’s lecture Welcome to the Tidyverse and meet Hadley in person. Hadley’s talks are always well-structured and worth listening.
Hadley Wickham has been a prime mover in releasing R upon the masses, enabling hordes of unsuspecting would-be researchers to process and visualize data in ways they never dreamed of. The tidyverse, the culmination of years of effort in the R language, is a universe of packages that facilitate a grammar of data, graphics, and modeling that allows even beginners to speak the language of data science fluently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminarium z udziałem prof. Philipa Zimbardo </title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/seminarium-z-udzialem-prof-philip-zimbardo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/seminarium-z-udzialem-prof-philip-zimbardo/</guid>
      <description>W sobotę (24.06) odbyło się na WSIiZ insprujące seminarium z udziałem on-line prof. P.Zimbardo.
Philip Zimbardo był w 1971 roku liderem sławnego Stanfordzkiego Eksperymentu Więziennego i świadkiem-ekspertem w sprawie więzienia Abu Ghraib. Autor wpływowych książek: The Time Paradox: The New Psychology of Time That Will Change Your Life i The Lucifer Effect: Understanding How Good People Turn Evil.
Warto zapoznać się z projektem Profesora Zimbardo:
Heroic Imagination Project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Data Science &amp; Programming Skills &amp; Tools</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/my-data-science-and-programming-skills-and-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/my-data-science-and-programming-skills-and-tools/</guid>
      <description>Here is a selection of my Data Science and Programming skills and tools that turned out to be helpful in my work and I believe are important for any Data Scientist as well.
The last update of this post was done: 2018-05-10.
Data Science SkillsData ManipulationEfficient data manipulation in R;
dplyr, data.table, reshape2.Working with dates and time-series;
lubridate, xts.Reproducible AnalysesRStudio IDE, Markdown, LaTeX;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources: Programming &amp; Data Science in R</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/resources-programming-data-science-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/resources-programming-data-science-in-r/</guid>
      <description>This post is an annotated bibliography of helpful resources for programming and doing Data Science in R. I will try to expand this list and add some short recommendations in the future.
The last update of this post was done: 2018-05-10.
Books (on-line &amp;amp; printed)Hadley Wickham, Advanced R
The book is designed primarily for R users who want to improve their programming skills and understanding of the language. It should also be useful for programmers coming to R from other languages, as it explains some of R’s quirks and shows how some parts that seem horrible do have a positive side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building static homepage with R &amp; blogdown</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/building-static-homepage-with-r-and-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/building-static-homepage-with-r-and-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>This new homepage is a static website generated in R (!) with the help of brilliant blogdown package by Yihui Xie. Hugo is the site engine and it also uses amazing Academic theme.
More about the blogdown R package you can find here: https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/
Some additional usefull posts:
Updating website with Hugo and BlogdownMaking SiteQuick Start setting up a custom domain with GitHub pages</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation of R package LimeRick on eRum</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/presentation-of-r-package-limerick-on-erum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/presentation-of-r-package-limerick-on-erum/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: The online static version of the presentation is available here: http://rpubs.com/kalimu/erum. Thank you for all the feedback!
In two days, from 12 to 14 October, 2016 in Poznan (Poland) will take place the conference “eRum 2016: european R users meeting“. I will give a talk about new R package: LimeRick. LimeRick enables close connection between two important open-source projects: R and LimeSurvey. LimeSurvey is the most advanced open-source system for on-line survey and Computer Aided Web Interviewing (CAWI) and together with R they offer advanced ecosystem for gathering and analyzing declarative data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My impression from Research Data Alliance (RDA) 7th Plenary Meeting in Tokyo</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/my-impression-from-research-data-alliance-rda-7th-plenary-meeting-in-tokyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/my-impression-from-research-data-alliance-rda-7th-plenary-meeting-in-tokyo/</guid>
      <description>Seventh RDA Plenary was organized in Tokyo in March 2016 in close partnership with the Japan Science and Technology Agency (JST). This was the first time a plenary took place in Asia. One of the reason was to expand the reach of the RDA far beyond America and Europe through increase in organization’s memberships from Asia region.
As one of the winners of the RDA Early Career European Researchers &amp;amp; Scientists Working with Data (RDA P7 Financial Support Programme), I had a unique opportunity and honor to see with my own eyes how activities in RDA look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checklist for R package submission to CRAN</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/checklist-for-r-package-submission-to-cran/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/checklist-for-r-package-submission-to-cran/</guid>
      <description>Version: 1.2The last update of this post: 2018-05-10.
Below is a checklist that I wrote for my own purposes. I helps me to be sure that I did what I should have done before release a new version of R package to CRAN. Maybe it will also help others.
See what new Hadley recommends:
(http://r-pkgs.had.co.nz/release.html).Update R &amp;amp; packages:Rall packagesRStudio (stable or preview version).Update your package:Check unit tests.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>