<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Event on Kamil Wais</title>
    <link>https://kalimu.github.io/tags/event/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Event on Kamil Wais</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2018 Kamil Wais · Site created in R &amp; Blogdown · v3.0.2</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kalimu.github.io/tags/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Tidyverse. Hadley Wickham lecture at Notre Dame University</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/welcome-to-the-tidyverse-hadley-wickham-lecture-at-notre-dame-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/welcome-to-the-tidyverse-hadley-wickham-lecture-at-notre-dame-university/</guid>
      <description>During my research visit at Notre Dame University I had the pleasure to participate in Hadley Wickham’s lecture Welcome to the Tidyverse and meet Hadley in person. Hadley’s talks are always well-structured and worth listening.
Hadley Wickham has been a prime mover in releasing R upon the masses, enabling hordes of unsuspecting would-be researchers to process and visualize data in ways they never dreamed of. The tidyverse, the culmination of years of effort in the R language, is a universe of packages that facilitate a grammar of data, graphics, and modeling that allows even beginners to speak the language of data science fluently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resovia R User Group (RRUG)</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/project/rrug/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/project/rrug/</guid>
      <description>[in Polish]
Od kwietnia 2016 roku działa pod patronatem WSIiZ w Rzeszowie Resovia R User Group (RRUG), czyli Rzeszowska Grupa Użytkowników R’a. Język programowania statystycznego R jest standardem zarówno wśród analityków sektora komercyjnego, administracyjnego, jak i pracowników naukowych. Globalna liczba jego użytkowników szacowana jest w milionach i stale rośnie. Wymianę doświadczeń związanych z analizą danych za pomocą R’a wspierają liczne grupy użytkowników R’a – lokalne społeczności analityków i programistów wspierające się w rozwoju zawodowym, naukowym i projektach analitycznych.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>