<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Kamil Wais</title>
    <link>https://kalimu.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Kamil Wais</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2018 Kamil Wais · Site created in R &amp; Blogdown · v3.7.2</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 21:07:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kalimu.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>shinyEventLogger</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/project/shinyeventlogger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 21:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/project/shinyeventlogger/</guid>
      <description>Logging Events in Shiny AppsR package shinyEventLogger is a logging framework dedicated for complex shiny apps. Different types of events can be logged (character string, value of a variable, multi-line output of a function, result of a unit test, custom error, warning, or diagnostic message). Each event can be logged with a list of parameters that are event-specific, common for a group of events, or common for all app events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closed Open Data</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/project/gus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/project/gus/</guid>
      <description>SummaryIn this research project we analyze barriers and bad practices in accessing Open Administrative Data in Poland.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genderizeR</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/project/genderizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/project/genderizer/</guid>
      <description>R package for gender prediction based on first namesThe package uses genderize.io API to predict gender from first names extracted from text vector. The accuracy of prediction could be control by two parameters: counts of a first name in the database and probability of prediction.
README, BugReports and development repository on GitHub: https://github.com/kalimu/genderizeR
The package webpage on CRAN:
http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/genderizeR
Article &amp;amp; Citations:When using the genderizeR R package in your work, please cite also the article:Kamil Wais, Gender Prediction Methods Based on First Names with genderizeR, The R Journal,Vol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ODGAR</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/project/odgar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/project/odgar/</guid>
      <description>ODGAR: Framework for Online Declarative Data Gathering, Analyzing, and Reporting.
BackgroundOff-line research paradigms are still dominant even in on-line survey techniques. Most online research techniques convert old-fashioned off-line questionnaires to HTML forms, so not only they do not exploit the full potential of Data Science &amp;amp; Internet Technologies, but they are outdated already by design. Thus, contemporary on-line techniques are not natively on-line—they are mainly off-line questionnaires converted into more or less advanced on-line HTML forms, but with inherited off-line characteristics (high burden and low value for respondents, non-equivalent information exchange).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polonia</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/project/polonia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/project/polonia/</guid>
      <description>W ramach projektu badawczego prowadzone są badania CAWI i PAPI wśród przedstawicieli środowisk polonijnych z całego świata, m.in.:
Polonijny Omnibus – badanie ankietowe przeprowadzane od 2011 r. wśród uczestników kolejnych edycji Światowych Festiwali Polonijnych Zespołów Folklorystycznych w Rzeszowie.Partnerami projektu są:
Rzeszowski Oddział Stowarzyszenia “Wspólnota Polska”Centrum Badań nad Polonią i Polakami na Świecie Uniwersytetu Rzeszowskiego</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>