<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Kamil Wais</title>
    <link>/categories/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Kamil Wais</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2018 Kamil Wais · Site created in R &amp; Blogdown · v3.0.1</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Wrażenia z pobytu na Uniwersytecie Notre Dame (USA)</title>
      <link>/post/wrazenia-z-pobytu-na-uniwersytecie-notre-dame-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/wrazenia-z-pobytu-na-uniwersytecie-notre-dame-usa/</guid>
      <description>Center for Research Computing (CRC)Od 1 sierpnia do 31 października 2017 r. miałem możliwość i ogromną satysfakcję gościć na Uniwersytecie Notre Dame w stanie Indiana. Pojechałem tam zaproszony przez dyrektora Center for Research Computing (CRC) prof. Jarka Nabrzyskiego, którego poznałem w Tokio rok wcześniej na konferencji plenarnej Research Data Alliance. W USA spędziłem trzy miesiące jako wizytujący assistant professor, przyglądając się pracy CRC, które jest jednym z kilku wydzielonych Centrów, działających na Uniwersytecie Notre Dame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Tidyverse. Hadley Wickham lecture at Notre Dame University</title>
      <link>/post/welcome-to-the-tidyverse-hadley-wickham-lecture-at-notre-dame-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/welcome-to-the-tidyverse-hadley-wickham-lecture-at-notre-dame-university/</guid>
      <description>During my research visit at Notre Dame University I had the pleasure to participate in Hadley Wickham’s lecture Welcome to the Tidyverse and meet Hadley in person. Hadley’s talks are always well-structured and worth listening.
Hadley Wickham has been a prime mover in releasing R upon the masses, enabling hordes of unsuspecting would-be researchers to process and visualize data in ways they never dreamed of. The tidyverse, the culmination of years of effort in the R language, is a universe of packages that facilitate a grammar of data, graphics, and modeling that allows even beginners to speak the language of data science fluently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminarium z udziałem prof. Philipa Zimbardo </title>
      <link>/post/seminarium-z-udzialem-prof-philip-zimbardo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/seminarium-z-udzialem-prof-philip-zimbardo/</guid>
      <description>W sobotę (24.06) odbyło się na WSIiZ insprujące seminarium z udziałem on-line prof. P.Zimbardo.
Philip Zimbardo był w 1971 roku liderem sławnego Stanfordzkiego Eksperymentu Więziennego i świadkiem-ekspertem w sprawie więzienia Abu Ghraib. Autor wpływowych książek: The Time Paradox: The New Psychology of Time That Will Change Your Life i The Lucifer Effect: Understanding How Good People Turn Evil.
Warto zapoznać się z projektem Profesora Zimbardo:
Heroic Imagination Project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building static homepage with R &amp; blogdown</title>
      <link>/post/building-static-homepage-with-r-and-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/building-static-homepage-with-r-and-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>This new homepage is a static website generated in R (!) with the help of brilliant blogdown package by Yihui Xie. Hugo is the site engine and it also uses amazing Academic theme.
More about the blogdown R package you can find here: https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/
Some additional usefull posts:
Updating website with Hugo and BlogdownMaking SiteQuick Start setting up a custom domain with GitHub pages</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>