<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DataScience on Kamil Wais</title>
    <link>https://kalimu.github.io/tags/datascience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DataScience on Kamil Wais</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2018 Kamil Wais · Site created in R &amp; Blogdown · v3.0.2</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kalimu.github.io/tags/datascience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Tidyverse. Hadley Wickham lecture at Notre Dame University</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/welcome-to-the-tidyverse-hadley-wickham-lecture-at-notre-dame-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/welcome-to-the-tidyverse-hadley-wickham-lecture-at-notre-dame-university/</guid>
      <description>During my research visit at Notre Dame University I had the pleasure to participate in Hadley Wickham’s lecture Welcome to the Tidyverse and meet Hadley in person. Hadley’s talks are always well-structured and worth listening.
Hadley Wickham has been a prime mover in releasing R upon the masses, enabling hordes of unsuspecting would-be researchers to process and visualize data in ways they never dreamed of. The tidyverse, the culmination of years of effort in the R language, is a universe of packages that facilitate a grammar of data, graphics, and modeling that allows even beginners to speak the language of data science fluently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Data Science &amp; Programming Skills &amp; Tools</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/my-data-science-and-programming-skills-and-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/my-data-science-and-programming-skills-and-tools/</guid>
      <description>Here is a selection of my Data Science and Programming skills and tools that turned out to be helpful in my work and I believe are important for any Data Scientist as well.
The last update of this post was done: 2018-05-06.
Data Science SkillsData ManipulationEfficient data manipulation in R;
dplyr, data.table, reshape2.Working with dates and time-series;
lubridate, xts.Reproducible AnalysesRStudio IDE, Markdown, LaTeX;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources: Programming &amp; Data Science in R</title>
      <link>https://kalimu.github.io/post/resources-programming-data-science-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kalimu.github.io/post/resources-programming-data-science-in-r/</guid>
      <description>This post is an annotated bibliography of helpful resources for programming and doing Data Science in R. I will try to expand this list and add some short recommendations in the future.
The last update of this post was done: 2018-05-06.
Books (on-line &amp;amp; printed)Hadley Wickham, Advanced R
The book is designed primarily for R users who want to improve their programming skills and understanding of the language. It should also be useful for programmers coming to R from other languages, as it explains some of R’s quirks and shows how some parts that seem horrible do have a positive side.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>